Guide to the John Marcum Papers M1726
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series 16. Mozambique, 1959-2013
  - UGEAN (General Union of Students from Black Africa under Portuguese Colonial Domination) (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - UNAMI (União Nacional Africana de Moçambique Independente)/Chagonga/UNAMO/MANC/MOLIMO (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - UNEMO (National Union of Mozambian Students/União Nacional de Estudantes de Moçambique) (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - UN Special Committee on Territories under Portuguese Administration binder on meetings held in Africa, 1962 (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - UN reports - refugee mental health, 1960-1964 (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - UN reports, 1962-1965 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - UN reports, 1965-1976 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - UN Security Council - Rome peace conference, 1992 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - U.S. State Department Foreign Service Despatches & telegrams [copies], 1962-1963 (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Artur Xavier Lambo Vilankuku (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - publications (Box 39, Folder 5)
    Includes singles issues or small runs from Não Vamos Esquecer, Revista de Imprensa, Soldier of Fortune, Committee of Returned Volunteers, U.S. Committee for Refugees, Africa Recovery, CSIS, & the Alicia Patterson Foundation.
  - clippings, 1959-2012 (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - notes, undated (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - chronological files, undated (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - chronological files, 1961-1965 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - chronological files, 1966-1972 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - chronological files, 1973-1977 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - chronological files, 1982-1988 (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - chronological files, 1995-2013 (Box 40, Folder 7)
- Series 17. Namibia/Southwest Africa
  - SWAPO (South-West Africa People's Organization) (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Windhoek Observer, Namibia Nachrichten, 1984 (Box 33, Folder 6)
- Series 18. New Caledonia, 1974-1998
  - binder of notes, reports, clippings, circa 1981-1983 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - binder of notes, correspondence, articles, circa 1982-1984 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - undated (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Marcum notes, South Pacific conference, 1974 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - 1981-1982 (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - 1983-1984 (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - clippings, 1984 (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - 1985 (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - clippings, 1985 (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - 1987-1988, 1998 (Box 41, Folder 10)
- Series 19. Nigeria - Eastern Region and NCNC, Biafra, 1954-1968
  Primarily late-1950s publications and ephemera promoting investment and development. Many are water-damaged. Material concerning Marcum's trips was filed elsewhere.
  - 1954-1956 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - 1957-1962 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - 1967 (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - 1968 (Box 42, Folder 4)
- Series 20. Postal System/Stamps (Box 42, Folder 5)
- Series 21. Sierra Leone (Box 42, Folder 6)
- Series 22. South Africa, 1963-1989
  - Marcum notebooks (Box 42, Folder 7)
    Labeled IIEE Trip Log; ACF Mission 1&2; untitled 1981, etc. South Africa notebooks also filed in Series 3, Notebooks.
  - undated (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Pan Africanist Congress/Robert Mangaliso Sobukwe, 1963 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Morley Zebulon Nkosi, 1963-1965, 1968 (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Nana Mahomo, 1963-1964 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Nana Mahomo - U.S. Tour, 1964 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Nana Mahomo, 1965-1989 (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Nana Mahomo (editor) - Black Star, Crisis & Change magazines, 1963-1966 (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - 1964-1970 (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Nadine Gordimer correspondence, 1971 (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - Seven Springs Center Symposium, 1978 (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - WPF (World Peace Foundation) / SAIIA (South African Institute of International Affairs) visit, 1984 (Box 43, Folders 11-12)
  - Berger/Godsell - A Future South Africa press kit, 1988 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - clippings, 1984-1986 (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - U.S. - South Africa, 1966-1968 (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - U.S. - South Africa, 1975-1995 (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - U.S. - South Africa policy clippings, 1988-1989 (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Sanctions clippings, 1988-1989 (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Soviets - South Africa, 1988-1989 (Box 44, Folder 7)
- Series 23. Soviet Union & Cuba - South Africa
  - papers, articles, etc. (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - publications (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - notes, papers, etc. (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Second Soviet-American Conference on Contemporary Sub-Saharan Africa (Moscow), 1984 (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Soviet Union in the Third World Conference (UC Berkeley), 1985 (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Seminar on Southern Africa Center of Studies on Africa & The Middle East/CFR (Havana), 1989 (Box 45, Folder 4)
- Series 24. Sudan, circa 1965-1978 (Box 45, Folder 5)
- Series 25. Togoland, 1955-1963
  - 1955-1956 (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - 1958 (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - 1960-1963 (Box 46, Folder 2)
- Series 26. Tunisia, circa 1961-1969 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  From file box labeled "Tunisia II"; no I is present. Other Tunisia material possibly in Chronological Series circa 1950s.
- Series 27. United States - Africa, 1955-2013
  - undated (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - 1960-1961 (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - 1962-1963 (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - 1964-1965 (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - 1966-1968 (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - 1970-1977 (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Adlai Stevenson Institute/Challenor, 1971 (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - 1978-1979 (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - 1982-2012 (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Africa - Economics/War Crisis [papers and clippings], 1988 (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Carter Center of Emory University - Myth Reality and the Future of Southern Africa, 1988 (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - Aspen Institute - Southern Africa Policy Forum, 1989 (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - USEUCOM (United States European Command) Conference on Southern Africa, 1989 (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - American Committee on Africa/George Houser (Box 49, Folder 3)
    Houser/ACA material on Angola is filed in the Angola series.
  - Council on Foreign Relations, 1963-1989 (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Council on Foreign Relations, 1990-1992 (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - Council on Foreign Relations, 1993-2013 (Box 49, Folder 6)
- Series 28. Zambia/Rhodesia, 1960-1970
  - undated (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - 1960-1961 (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - 1960-1961 (Box 49, Folder 9)
  - 1962-1963 (Box 57, Folder 1)
  - 1964-1970 (Box 57, Folder 2)
- Series 29. Photographs & slides
  - misc. photographs of or including Marcum (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - passports (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - identification cards & papers (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Berlin, 1950s (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Nigeria, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Ford Foundation trip with Phil Curtin, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    Negatives, copy prints, and related photographs also filed here. Includes a photo of Patrice Lumumba and images from Senegal, Guinea, and elsewhere. Some of these photos were published in an issue of The New Leader (December 1, 1958) credited to Marcum. Also contains a letter from Phil's wife Anne and an unsent postcard by Marcum.
  - Mauritania, Dahomey, Guinea, etc., 1958 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - United States Information Service photographs of coctail party, late 1950s? (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Angola trip with George Houser, January-February 1962 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - color slides- Angola, January-February 1962 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - damaged slides - Angola, January-February 1962 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    With note from Marcum's father Arthur referring to "dunked film"
  - slides - Africa? (all but two severely underexposed), 1963 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Marcum with African students at Lincoln University, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Photo Info-Senegal photographs of outdoor event, c.1966-1967 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - slides - Africa, developed January & September 1974 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - slides - South Pacific [possibly Tahiti and Rarotonga], developed November 1974 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - slides - South Africa, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - slides - South Africa, 1981 [developed January 1982] (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - slides - unidentified locations, some family, developed March 1984 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - slides - USSR, developed August 1984 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - slides - South Africa, developed December 1984 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - slides - France, most developed December 1984 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - slides - South Africa, developed February 1985 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - IIS conference - Moscow, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Angola election, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - "Mostly Labeled Slides" [Nigeria, Algeria, etc.], developed 1965, 1974, 1977, etc (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - misc. photos - Africa (Box 9, Folder 2)
    Includes the following: Republic of the Congo flag-raising ceremony in Kunzu/Leopoldville; Bureau de l'Information du Haut-Commissariat de la Republique en A.E.F. [Afrique-Équatoriale Française] photo of General De Gaulle shaking hands with Habib Bourguiba [Brazzaville 1958?]; group portrait of Juvento party in Togo, 1958; Joseph Kasa-Vubu and ABAKO rally, January 4th, 1959 "just before the Belgian Congo riots"; Christmas card with a photo of women in Upper Volta c.1976; a few postcards
  - misc. photos - Africa (mostly unidentified) (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - unidentified photos - Africa, circa 1960 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    Series of uncaptioned prints, including images of Albert Schweitzer and a tour group (possibly the Harriman trip?)
  - Angola - revolution, 1960-1968 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    Includes several captioned photos from GRAE's Information Ministry; damaged print of UPA's first headquarters in Leopoldville 1960; damaged RPC of Roberto & Adoula; Roberto & GRAE marching in Leopoldville; damaged print of Roberto, Adoula and Kunzika 1963; two photos from Emmanuel Kunzika depicting Luvaka 5/17/1968
  - South Africa (Box 9, Folder 6)
    Mostly commercial prints promoting travel and economic investment, many with South African Railways stamp. Also some postcards, and three copy prints of PAC demonstrations
  - misc. slides- Africa, etc. (Box 9, Folder 7)
    Includes images from Kenya, the Congo, Tanzania, as well as New York City, and elsewhere (possibly England?). One is dated 1958.
  - slides - personal/family (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - film in cannisters, envelope (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Series 30. Media
  - 30.1 audio reels
    Many tapes, including those with labels, were found to be blank.
    - This Is Angola. Dr. John Markham [sic]. Tracks 1; 4 [7" reel, mailed in package dated 1969] (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Duplicate of Angola Tape 1+2 [7" reel] (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Duplicate of Angola Tapes 3+4 - 5+6 [7" reel] (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Parts 2+4 [7" reel] (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Dr. John Marcum. 1. S.W. Africa. News in Depth Interview. Mr. Jacob Kuangua. 2. Sierra Leone Receives Independence. Dr. John Marcum. With Dr. William Fitzjohn. News In Depth. WRCU - The Colgate Community Radio Service [7" reel] (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Southern Africa Symposium. May 12, 1967. Parts 1&3. Amb. Matthews - good. Amb. Mohala [?]. Counselor Kaenga [7" reel], 1967-05-12 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - unidentifed 7" reel [Irish brand] (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - unidentifed 7" reel [Irish brand] (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - unidentifed 7" reel [Irish brand] (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - unidentifed 7" reel [Nassau brand] (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Copy of Dr. Marcum [illeg. - Pres. of North Rhodesia?] (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - unidentifed 7" reel [no box] (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - unidentifed 7" reel [no box] (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Tape 5+6. Side 1. Forest of Muengo: UPA song; Speech in Kicongo Addressed to Houser & Marcum; Trans. into French; Vivas; Songs & drills, more vivas; Good viva chorus; Speech in Kicongo; Songs. Side 2. Songs; John & George English & French in Fuesse; Petersen explains the four preceeding songs (French); Interview of Bernardo _____; French-Kicongo mostly; Fast @ 190 for4 song; slow @218 for interview with Fuesse nurse (French); end 260 (good for ERA); George in English; Petersen in French (good); Mr. Frederico in Kicongo; JUVENTA songs, trans. by Petersen [5" reel] (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Tape 7+8. Songs. Ngunga. Petersen interview [5" reel] (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Tape 9+10. Side 1. Petersen (French) talks about ALIZO MPLA, Christian & Protestant missions; Prov. government; JUPA's role (incl. problems of teaching while being bombed); Forced labor interviews (George intro, Petersen asks questions, mostly in Kicongo) [5" reel] (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Batista. 2nd interview and Kendualu speech. 2 [5" reel] (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Pat Paden [5" reel] (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Olga Guillot Sings [5" reel] (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Sp255 Lesson #3. Repetition - Idoims - Practical Excercises 10-4-55 [5" reel] (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - unidentified 5" reel [Scotch brand] (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - unidentified 5" reel [Irish brand, probably blank] (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - unidentified 5" reel [no box] (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - unidentified 5" reel [no box] (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - unidentified 3" reel [Dictape brand box, Grundig brand reel] (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Kunzika and Dombele [?] [3" reel] (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - 30.2 audiocassettes
    - Rand Afrikaans University. Rektor Dr. J.D. DeLange. 8/16 (Box 5, Cassette 1)
    - Luncheon - Soweto (Box 5, Cassette 2)
    - University of W. Cape (Box 5, Cassette 3)
    - University of Lesotha. Monday, August 31 (Box 5, Cassette 4)
    - University of North Soweto Luncheon speeches, #55. 8/18/81 (Box 5, Cassette 5)
    - University of Witwaterswand, Slide Show of University (Box 5, Cassette 6)
    - University of Pretoria - V.P. Youbert and Profs Botany, Chem, Religion, Econ (Box 5, Cassette 7)
    - Kwazulu - Chief Butheleze (Box 5, Cassette 8)
    - Technikon (Box 5, Cassette 9)
    - University of Pretoria. Rector-Joubert (Manpower Part) (Box 5, Cassette 10)
    - Conference on South Africa. Wed. PM Tape #1 (Box 6, Cassette 11)
    - Conference on South Africa. Wed. PM/Thurs AM Tape #2 (Box 6, Cassette 12)
    - Conference on South Africa. Thurs AM Tape #3 (Box 6, Cassette 13)
    - Conference on South Africa. Conclusion, Thurs AM 2PM Tape #4 (Box 6, Cassette 14)
    - Conference on South Africa. Conclusion, Thurs 3:45PM Tape #5 (Box 6, Cassette 15)
    - Siphu Bothelezi - 25 Min. (Box 6, Cassette 16)
    - Sipho Buthelezi - Aspects of The Development of Struggle in South Africa January 26, 1978, 1978-01-26 (Box 6, Cassette 17)
    - unidentified audiocassette [Scotch brand] (Box 6, Cassette 18)
    - Songs of Chimurenga, Recorded Live in a Guerilla Camp. Zimbabwe African National Liberation Army (Box 6, Cassette 19)
    - A Conversation with Jonas Savimbi, CSIS 10/2/89, 1989-10-02 (Box 6, Cassette 20)
    - John Marcum - Meet The Press 1/4/76, 1976-01-04 (Box 6, Cassette 21)
    - John Marcum - Meet The Press January 4, 19/76, 1976-01-04 (Box 6, Cassette 22)
    - John Marcum - NBC Meet The Press 1/4/76, 1976-01-04 (Box 6, Cassette 23)
    - John Marcum, UCSC, third availability. Liberation of Angola. 2 cuts. duplicate of UC Audio News Service Programming 11/12 (Box 6, Cassette 24)
    - English: USIS Cape Town John Marcum & T. Diebel. Post Moscow Summit 6/13/88, 1988-06-13 (Box 6, Cassette 25)
  - 30.3 videocassettes
    - Leading the Way: Black Trade Unions in South Africa. LVBT-026-v. Labor Institute of Public Affairs (Box 5, Cassette 1)
    - The Read Organization. Gimme a Break, Gimma Book. Max Katz & Associates (Box 5, Cassette 2)
    - World in Focus. Council of Foreign Relations (Box 5, Cassette 3)
    - The Luanda Massacre (Oct. 31-Nov. 2, 1992) and Its Aftermath. Free Angola Information Service [press release enclosed] (Box 5, Cassette 4)
    - unidentified video [with Stanford University logo stamp] (Box 5, Cassette 5)
  - 30.4 computer diskette: Africa9-96_1; ACE[?] Review, 1 computer disk(s) (Box 6)
- Series 31. Publications
  Many magazines, newspapers and other published material are single issues or clippings interfiled in the Chronological or subject files.
  - 31.1 magazines
    - Africa Confidential, 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Africa Confidential, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Africa Confidential, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Africa Confidential, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Africa Confidential, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Africa Confidential, 1969-1971 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Africa Special Report/Africa Report, 1957-1969 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Awake! Vol.56 No.23, December 8, 1975 (Box 33, Folder 4)
      With cover story: "Atrocities Against Chistians in Malawi: When Will They Stop?" Enclosed with letter to Marcum.
  - 31.2 newspapers
    For the most arranged chronologically. Some issues may not be complete. Clipped pages are filed here but not described.
    - Nigerian Citizen no.534 June 19, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - West African Pilot vol.XX no.6069 July 30, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - New Africa vol.9 no.1985 August 6, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Nigerian Spokesman vol.XV no.4070 August 6, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Eastern Outlook vol.VII no.15 August 8, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Eastern Sentinel vol.II no. 654 August 8, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Daily Comet vol.II no.224 August 16, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Contains article mentioning Marcum visit.
    - The Listener vol.8 no.91 August 20, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Terre Africaine no.4 November 1958 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Poor condition.
    - Terre Africaine No.5 December 1958 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Ghana Times vol.I no.244 December 13, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Sawaba no.10 August 18, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Le Regroupment no.4 October 11, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      organe bi-mensuel de l'Union Progressiste Senegalaise
    - Le Regroupment no.5 November 1, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Fraternite, 1959-1963 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      2nd Ed. Speciale supplement with portrait of Houphet-Bougney and song "L'Abidjanaise"
      no.20 September 4, 1959
      no.71 August 26, 1960
      no.72 September 2, 1960
      no. 78 October 14, 1960
      no.96 February 17, 1961
      no.97 February 24, 1961
      no.126 September 22, 1961
      no.135 November 24, 1961
      no.193 January 4, 1963
    - Unite Togolaise, 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Abidjan Matin no.2738 August 31, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - L'Homme Nouveau no.2 March 8, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - The Liberian Age vol.15 no.33 April 22, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - The Liberian Age vol.15 no.69 August 29, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Carrefour Africain No.22 August 21, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Carrefour Africain No.23 August 28, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Carrefour Africain No.25 September 11, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Contact vol.3 no.18 September 10, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Presence Chretienne no.10 October 1960 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - La Voix de la Nation Angolaise/A Voz da na Cao Angolana, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - El Moudjahid, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - African Mail no.50 January 31, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - The Courier, Portuguese Africa Supplement July 1, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Evening News vol.III no.778 September 3, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Evening News vol.IV no.1033 July 1, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Unidade Angolana no.1 December 1961 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Unidade Angolana February 4, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - The Spark no.125 May 7, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Le Moniteur Africain no.250 July 13, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Anti-Apartheid News March 1966 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - La Semaine no.760 March 26, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Le Progres Supplement "Six Ans de Lutte en Angola" April 2, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Daily Listener vol.17 no.247 March 3, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Daily Listener vol.17 no.248 March 4, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Addis-Soir no.19 December 12, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - The Standard no.19063 August 28, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - The Standard no.19157 December 16, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Ghanaian Times no.5719 April 24, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Daily News no.1390 October 5, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - The Ethiopian Herald vol. XXXIV no.417 May 17, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - New Caledonia newspapers, 1982, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      Corail no.127 August 27, 1982
      Corail no.128 September 3, 1982
      Fetuu-Aho no.75 August 19, 1982
      A Notre Avis, Supplement au no.2 du journal Rendre Compte [no date]
      L'Evenement, Supplement a L'Avenir no. 860, 1982
      Les Nouvelles Caledoniennes no. 3383 September 1, 1982
      Les Nouvelles Caledoniennes no. 3384 September 2, 1982
      Les Nouvelles Caledoniennesno. 3385 September 3, 1982
      Les Nouvelles Caledoniennes no. 3386 September 5, 1982
      Les Nouvelles Caledoniennes no.4269 August 9, 1985
      Les Nouvelles Caledoniennes no.4271 August 12, 1985
    - South African newspapers January 21, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      The Citizen; The Natal Mercury; The Star; Rand Daily Mail
    - Jornal De Angola, 1984-1988 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Jornal De Angola, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Terra Angolana no.29 September 23, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Novo Jornal no.29 August 8, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - US & Soviet newspapers, 1956-1985 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      Moscow News no.45 June 6, 1956
      Moscow News no.50 June-July 1984
      Young Socialist February 1976
      The Daily Californian vol.XVII no.26 February 15, 1985
      Minneapolis Star and Tribune supplement "Africa by Robert B. Hewitt" 1959
- Series 32. Posters & maps
  - United States - Africa (Map-folder 69)
  - political posters, France (Map-folder 70)
  - political posters, Great Britain (Map-folder 71)
  - Cuba, Guatemala, New Caledonia, Fiji (Map-folder 72)
  - map of People's Revolt June 17, 1953, East Germany (Map-folder 73)
  - Soviet posters (Map-folder 74)
  - African posters, maps, etc. (Map-folder 75)
- Series 33. Miscellaneous
  - Edmond Keller articles & papers (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - wallet with ephemera including notes, business cards, etc. (Box 56, Folder 4)
  - reviews of Marcum books (Box 66, Folder 1)
  - citations of Marcum writing (Box 66, Folder 2)
  - Marcum ephemera - business cards, certificates, etc. (Box 66, Folder 3)
  - other ephemera (Box 66, Folder 4)
  - miscellaneous article clippings (Box 66, Folder 5)
  - realia (Box 67)
    Angola t-shirt with photo ID of Marcum (from 1992 IFES trip); traditional hat with metal crossed-swords pin; small penant with insect (mosquito?) insignia; water-damaged roll of FNLA 5-Angolares stamps; two LPs - Angola Freedom Songs (Folkways FD 5442) - cover only & Angola: A Vitoria e Certa! (Paredon P1002)_ - sealed copy.
  - address books and files (Box 68)